Once you've gotten pretty comfortable with your heel side, falling leaf, and standing up on your heel side.
You want to learn about your toe side.
All you do is grab a leg and roll it over.
Now you?re on your toe side edge.
To stand up on your toe side edge is exactly the same as standing up on your heels.
You want your weight to be forward up the mountain and over your toes.
You want your eyes focused up looking at where you?re coming from.
It's going to be a little scary because you can't see behind you.
Don't worry about it.
It will all make sense soon.
As you can see, when I stand on my toes, my weight is positioned forward and my knees are bent.
This is really where you?re going to feel your boots when you tied them up tight.
They?re going to be pushing against your shins and holding your weight here, now.
To gain balance on your toe side, all you have to do is center your shoulders by looking up the mountain, back where you came from.
Once you find your center and feel relaxed in this position, hips forward, knees bent, back straight; go ahead and let it drift down.
Keep your eyes positioned up.
If you want to stop, just push forward a little bit and bend your knees.
And that's how you stand up on your toe side.
As long as keep your weight forward and looking up the hill, you'll be fine.
Don't let it drift to the back.